<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
    <text>.45 ACP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_descr">
    <text>A standard .45 round with a standard core and a full-jacketed bullet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
    <text>.45 ACP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
    <text>.45 ACP Hydro-Shock</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_descr">
    <text>A Hydro-Shock round with improved charasteristics from .45 ACP. It has a hollow-point bullet with a good stopping effect.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
    <text>.45 Hydro</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
    <text>12x70 Buckshot</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x70-buck_descr">
    <text>A 12 gauge shell full of led, 6mm shot. Designed to spread in flight, encompassing a larger area than slugs or darts. Common ammunition good for killing the many mutants of the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
    <text>12x70 Shot</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
    <text>12x76 Slug</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_descr">
    <text>This 12 caliber slug was made for hunting large animals, with excellent stopping power and an armor piercing effect.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
    <text>12x76 Slug</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
    <text>5.45x39 PSU</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_descr">
    <text>Used in assault rifles from the Warsaw Pact era. Its carbide core produces an armor piercing effect.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
    <text>5.45x39 PSU</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
    <text>5.45x39</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_descr">
    <text>Used in assault rifles from the Warsaw Pact era. This ammunition provides a nice reduction in recoil and an increase in range that is comparable to the 7.62mm.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
    <text>5.45x39</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
    <text>5.56x45 mm AP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_descr">
    <text>This NATO 5.56 has a very high piercing ability. While typically used in small arms, it is quite effective against body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
    <text>5.56x45 AP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
    <text>5.56x45</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_descr">
    <text>This NATO cartridge, known as SS109, has quite the ballistic impact.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
    <text>5.56x45</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
    <text>7.62x54 7H1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_descr">
    <text>This 7.62mm sniper cartridge, filled with bullets equipped with a steel core, has a much improved ballistic and piercing ability when compare to the standard 7.62mm.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
    <text>7.62x54 7H1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
    <text>7.62x54 PP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_descr">
    <text>Standard 7.62 rounds.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
    <text>7.62x54 PP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
    <text>9x18</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_descr">
    <text>This cartridge, with its steel core and lead-cover, has good stopping power, but it is quite ineffective against body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
    <text>9x18</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
    <text>9x18 +P+</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_descr">
    <text>Bullets with more stopping power. The designation +P+ indicates a hot load, resulting in more pressure in the firing chamber, resulting in increased muzzle velocity and increase wear on the weapon. They have about a third more gunpowder. Not effective against armored foes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
    <text>9x18 +P+</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
    <text>9x19 FMJ</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_descr">
    <text>This cheap 9x19mm bullet with a full metal jacket is widely distributed. It is ineffective against body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
    <text>9x19 FMJ</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
    <text>9x19 JHP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_descr">
    <text>Used in police and civilian self-defense weapons, this ammo has good stopping action is not prone to bounce. It is ineffective against body armor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
    <text>9x19 JHP</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
    <text>9x39 mm SP-6</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-ap_descr">
    <text>This cartridge of SP-6 ammo is equipped with a bullet containting a partially open core of hardened steel. It's quite loud and requires a suppressor for quiet shooting. It has a good armor piercing effect.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
    <text>9x39 SP-6</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
    <text>9x39 SP-5</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_descr">
    <text>This bi-metallic shelled sniper cartridge is quite loud. Behind the steel core is lead. For quiet shots, you'll need a suppressor.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
    <text>9x39 SP-5</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss">
    <text>Gauss Cell</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-m209">
    <text>Grenade M203</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-m209_descr">
    <text>This M203 grenade shell has an explosion zone of about 5 meters. It can be also used in the in the FN F2000.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-m209_s">
    <text>M203</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-og-7b">
    <text>OG-7B</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-og-7b_descr">
    <text>An anti-personnel grenade. With a RPG-7v, you can launch to distances much farther than what you would throw to with your hands.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
    <text>OG-7B</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-vog-25">
    <text>Grenade VOG-25</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-vog-25_descr">
    <text>This grenade, usable in the GP-25, OTs-14 Groza, and the RG-6, has a blast radius of 5 meters.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
    <text>VOG-25</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope">
    <text>PSO-1m</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_descr">
    <text>This widespread optical sight has a 4x magnification. Installs on weapons using the standard dovetail mount.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_detector">
    <text>MSS-2x</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_detector_descr">
    <text>This scope has thermal imaging capability and magnification up to 4x. The scope can be mounted on a weapon using the dovetail mount used by the Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision">
    <text> NSPU-3</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision_descr">
    <text>Night vision sight with a fixed magnification of 4x. Designed for combat in the dark. The scope can be mounted on a weapon using the dovetail mount used by the Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat">
    <text>ACOG 4x</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom_descr">
    <text>Adjustable rangefinder with an adjustable magnification of 1.6x to 4x. It can be attached to a standard NATO mount, also called the Picatinny rail.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_descr">
    <text>Optical sight with a fixed magnification of 4x. Most commonly used on small arms and light weapons firing from medium to large distances. It can be attached to a standard NATO mount, also called the Picatinny rail.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk">
    <text>ACOG 1.6x (dusk)</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk_descr">
    <text>A 1.6x scope produced in the NATO countries. Designed for combat at dusk. It can be attached to a standard NATO mount, also called the Picatinni rail.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision">
    <text>ACOG 4x (night)</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision_descr">
    <text>Designed for shots into the dark, this scope has built in night vision. With a magnification of 4x, picking off enemies at long range shouldn't be a problem. It can be attached to a standard NATO mount, also called the Picatinny rail.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6">
    <text>ACOG 1.6x</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6_descr">
    <text>With a low magnification of 1.6x, this scope is designed for small to medium range shoot outs. The scope can be mounted on a weapon using the dovetail mount used by the Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7">
    <text>POC-1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7_descr">
    <text>Optical sight fixed at 2.7x. Optimized for a fighting at medium ranges, as well as for use in urban conditions. The scope can be mounted on a weapon using the dovetail mount used by the Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_silencer">
    <text>Suppressor</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_silencer_descr">
    <text>Designed to mask the flame and sound of a weapon firing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_f1">
    <text>F1 Grenade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_f1_descr">
    <text>Hand grenades. The shrapnel can penetrate the average bulletproof vest. Has a range of up to 7m.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_launcher">
    <text>GP-25</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_launcher_descr">
    <text>A grenade launcher for the Akm 74/2 and Akm 74/2U. Uses VOG-25.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203">
    <text>M203</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203_descr">
    <text>Modification of single-shot grenade launcher M203 with a shortened three-inch barrel. It can be attached to a standard NATO mount, also called the Picatinny rail. Due to a change mounting, this model has found very wide application throughout the world.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_rgd5">
    <text>RGD5 Grenade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_rgd5_descr">
    <text>Hand grenade with a small shrapnel burst of about 5 meters.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_smoke">
    <text>Smoke Grenade</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_grenade_smoke_descr">
    <text>Manual smoke grenade. Forms a veil of smoke in about 10 seconds.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_knife">
    <text>Knife</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_abakan">
    <text>AN-94 Abakan</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74">
    <text>AKM-74/2</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74u">
    <text>AKM-74/2U</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag">
    <text>Snag's AKM-74/2U</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74u_snag_descr">
    <text>The spec-ops version of shortened AK rifle. Equipped with a Kobra reflex sight and silencer. It also uses a 40 rounds extended magazine.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_beretta">
    <text>Beretta 92fs</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_bm16">
    <text>Sawn-off BM16</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_bm16_descr">
    <text>A conventional, but lightweight and compact shotgun. One of the most common types of weapons used by bandits as it's suitable for concealed carrying and is very effective in close combat.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_colt1911">
    <text>Colt 1911</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_nimble">
    <text>Desert Dragon</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_nimble_descr">
    <text>Based on the Desert Eagle, this weapon offers unprecedented accuracy in the battlefield.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_eagle">
    <text>Desert Eagle</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fn2000">
    <text>FN F2000</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fn2000_nimble">
    <text>FN F2000S</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fort">
    <text>Fort-12</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fort_snag">
    <text>Snag's Fort</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_g36">
    <text>G36K</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_g36_nimble">
    <text>G36C</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_gauss">
    <text>Gauss Cannon</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_groza">
    <text>OTs-14 Groza</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_groza_descr">
    <text>An assault rifle combined with a grenade launcher. It is a very good type of assault rifle for the Zone conditions: it is compact, reliable, but universal and powerful. It is one of the favorite rifles of the military stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble">
    <text>Storm</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble_descr">
    <text>The modification of the standard OTs-14 Groza, created specifically for special forces operating in the Zone. Equipped with permanent silencer and PO4x34 scope.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_hpsa">
    <text>Browning Hi-Power</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_hpsa_descr">
    <text>Modified pistol from the first half of the twentieth century. Despite its age it still remains quite popular.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_l85">
    <text>L85</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_lr300">
    <text>M4A1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_mp5">
    <text>HK MP5</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_mp5_descr">
    <text>This submachine gun is very popular due to its reliability, ease of use, and great accuracy. It has been adpoted by the armies and police units of many countries. After its appearance on the black market, it has made its way to the zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_mp5_nimble">
    <text>Frazer</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_mp5_nimble_descr">
    <text>Experimental submachine gun, based on the HK MP5. It uses .45 ACP ammo and it's equipped qith a Docter reflex sight. The aim of its creators was a weapon for the new generation: Heavy and rapid-fire, but at the same time accurate.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pb">
    <text>PB / 6P9</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pkm_zulus">
    <text>Zulu's RPK-74 </text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pkm_zulus_descr">
    <text>This gun belonged to Zulu. The modifcations to this sample were to increase the capacity for cartridges and a specially robustly designed retracting mechanism. It has also mounted a Kobra collimator sight. Modifications increased the mass of the weapon, although to the previous owner it wasn't a problem.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pm">
    <text>Makarov PM</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pm_actor">
    <text>Ceremonial Makarov</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pm_actor_descr">
    <text>Engraving reads: "For the successful completion of high-risk assignments and for displaying valor and courage".</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_protecta">
    <text>Armsel Striker</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_protecta_nimble">
    <text>Eliminator</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rg6">
    <text>RG-6</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rg6_descr">
    <text>Revolver style grenade launcher. The chamber drum is formed with 6 barrels. Designed to combat the enemies in bunkers, it is also useful in an attack on a well-guarded facility or in battle with a particularly tenacious creature.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rp">
    <text>RPK-74</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rp_descr">
    <text>Has a manually modified belt feed. Despite its weight and poor accuracy, it is used fairly widely in The Zone. It is primarily used to suppress enemies superior in numbers and sweep out mutants.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rpg7">
    <text>RPG-7U</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig220">
    <text>SIG P220</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig220_nimble">
    <text>Alpiets</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig220_nimble_descr">
    <text>Unique model of the SIG P220. It was released to a small party for use in an unknown riot. This modification is characterized by increased magazine capacity due to used 9 mm Parabellum cartrigde, barrel made of a strong steel, and polymer casing trunk.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig550">
    <text>SIG SG 550</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig550_descr">
    <text>Representative of the new family of assault rifles. With its high reliability and accuracy it is one of the best examples of this class of weapon. In the Zone it is found infrequently and is a bit expensive. Usually its specially bought by experienced stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok">
    <text>Strelok's SIG SG 550</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok_descr">
    <text>An sniper version of assault rifle that was obviously not released yesterday. Clearly shows that the previous owner handled his weapons carefully. The rifle is fully enumerated and its parts carefully fitted to each other, allowing a modest increase in the lethal force. At the butt is has, neatly carved, the letter "S" and 16 small marks.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12">
    <text>SPAS-12</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12_nimble">
    <text>Carabineer</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12_nimble_descr">
    <text>Based on the SPAS-12. Like its predecessor, the weapon provides automatic fire, but much more effeciently. It is also equipped with a Trijicon reflex sight.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svd">
    <text>SVDm-2</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svd_descr">
    <text>This rifle was widely used in all operations of the Soviet and Russian armies since 1960. It proved itself to be an exceptionally reliable and handy weapon. In the Zone it is preferred by the experienced stalkers of the Duty faction which hunt mutants.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble">
    <text>Lynx</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble_descr">
    <text>While it looks no different, this model has improved accuracy and power over the standard SVDm-2. It is also equipped with a 1P59 scope instead of standard PSO.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svu">
    <text>SVUmk-2</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble">
    <text>SVU2-A</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble_descr">
    <text>A sniper rifle with an increased rate of fire, further developing on the SVUmk-2. It comes with a PKS-07 scope instead of standard PSO. Previously belonged to Max, the legendary leader of the group Freedom.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_toz34">
    <text>TOZ34</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_toz34_descr">
    <text>A widespread hunting rifle with sufficient accuracy and good stopping action provides better protection against mutants than the standard pistol. Very cheap and affordable compared to most weapons, so it is actively used by novices and bandits on the outskirts of the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel">
    <text>Unknown weapon</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel_descr">
    <text>It is unknown what this weapon does. Pressing the trigger does nothing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_usp">
    <text>HK USP Compact</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_usp_descr">
    <text>A reliable weapon. As a quality compact close-range weapon, it is very popular among the Zone veterans.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_usp_nimble">
    <text>March</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_usp_nimble_descr">
    <text>A modification of the HK USP pistol, which is called USP Match. It distinguishes itself by its barrel weight, which provides counterbalance to the weapon's recoil, greatly improving follow up target tracking. According to rumors, this weapon once belonged to a mercenary nicknamed Wolfhound.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_val">
    <text>SR-3M Vikhr</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_vintorez">
    <text>VSS Vintorez</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_vintorez_descr">
    <text>A special sniper rifle designed for noiseless and flameless sniper fire and equipped with an integrated silencer. It can pierce any bulletproof vest at a range of 400 meters. It is a weapon highly valued by stalkers of any level.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble">
    <text>Tide</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble_descr">
    <text>Based on the silent VSS Vintorez, this weapon designed for the special forces has an extended magazine and it is equipped with a modern 1P29 scope.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_walther">
    <text>Walther P99</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300">
    <text>TOZ-194</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_descr">
    <text>A smooth-bore Russian pump-action shotgun made for use in the most hostile environment. It is very reliable. All its details are covered with anticorrosive coating.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper">
    <text>Predator</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper_descr">
    <text>The former property of Trapper. It's a modification of powerful Russian KS-23 shotgun, adapted to shooting 12ga shells.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss_cardan">
    <text>Handicraft Battery</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom">
    <text>ACOG "Measure"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_abakan_descr">
    <text>This modern machine gun was designed to replace the aging AKM-74/2. One of the main features is its ability to fire burts of 2 rounds with high accuracy (at a distance of hundred meters of the two bullets fall into one point). This greatly increases the chances of hitting a target with both bullets giving added stopping power.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74_descr">
    <text>Assault rifle designed in 1974, heralding the switch to a smaller standard caliber in the Warsaw pact nations. Massive compensator can reduce and even more so not too much recoil that positively affects the precision and accuracy of fire in all modes of fire. In addition, the device is simple and reliable weapon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_ak74u_descr">
    <text>Although its size and attributes are more fitting to an SMG, the firing mechanism is almost identical to the AKM-74/2. The small size of the weapon makes it easy to use in urban and cramped up conditions. Its shortcomings are its small sight range and a tendency to overheat quick.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_colt1911_descr">
    <text>An improved model of the pistol which became a classic automatic weapon. It is still produced by dozens, if not hundreds, of manufacturers. The only drawback is the small magazine, however, the powerful round more than compensates for this.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_eagle_descr">
    <text>A real hand cannon. Big, heavy gun of high destruction potential. It was developed as special weapon for hunting big game and also for some types of sport shooting on steel silhouette targets at the distance of 50 meters and more. Its high price, weight and size make this gun unpopular in the Zone. Its dimensions and lack of a suppressor makes this weapon a bad choice for stealth.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fn2000_descr">
    <text>This futuristic-looking weapon is a mass-produced automatic grenade launcher. Equipped with a 40-mm grenade launcher, sight, and computerized fire control module. Despite its awkward look, it is highly ergonomic, easily fired in all modes, and highly reliable.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fn2000_nimble_descr">
    <text>This version of F2000 futuristic rifle is not equipped with a grenade launcher, but it is lighter, more handy and can be equipped with all versions of ACOG scope.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fort_descr">
    <text>A sidearm of Ukranian production, designed for police and military forces.  Has much better ballistic and ergonomic qualities than the outdated PMm, along with a larger clip size. The models that are widely used in the zone are generally first generation, and as such have their share of problems. Still in high demand from stalkers due to its versatility and improved characteristics.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_fort_snag_descr">
    <text>Treated almost like a family heirloom, old but lethal Fort, which was a long time ago modified by Snag's uncle with his own hands.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_g36_descr">
    <text>This assault rifle is a first class example of modern weapons - light, durable and ergonomic. The embodiment of the new trends in automatic rifles, the firing mechanism is powered on a short course gas piston.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_g36_nimble_descr">
    <text>The compact version of G36 assault rifle, equipped with an Eotech collimator sight.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_l85_descr">
    <text>This rifle features a four-optic sight, high precision single shot, and a high potential for modernization. When firing bursts, the accuracy drops sharply. When firing in automatic, it has a tendancy to delay. These short comings have lead to a mass modernization of most of the weapons for the black market shops in the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_lr300_descr">
    <text>Heavily used by the U.S military, the shorter and lighter variant of a very popular M16 assault rifle. The M4A1 carbine is a fully automatic variant of the basic M4 carbine, intended for special operations use. It comes with Picatinny rail and RIS foregrip, so can be equipped with a scope and grenade launcher.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pb_descr">
    <text>This pistol, based on the Makarov PM, was designed in the second half of the twentieth century for various intelligence agencies. It is now considered obsolete, but in skill hands it is still quite effective.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_pm_descr">
    <text>The legacy of the Soviet era, the Makarov PM is on the best representitives in the compact self defense weapons class. Small in size, very reliable, and easy to use and maintain. Its shortcomings include a small range, weak accuracy, low efficiency of bullets, and (in comparison with modern guns of the same class) has a rather large mass.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_protecta_descr">
    <text>Smooth-bore shotgun of revolver-type developed for soldiers to provide high firepower. The main advantages are high magazine capacity and practicable fire rate, but the downsides are its big size and mass, so as slow reloading speed.It is a rare find in the Zone, mainly used for mop-up operations against monsters in enclosed spaces.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_protecta_nimble_descr">
    <text>Smooth-bore shotgun of revolver-type developed for soldiers to provide high firepower. The main advantages are high magazine capacity and practicable fire rate, but the downsides are its big size and mass, so as slow reloading speed. It is a rare find in the Zone, mainly used for mop-up operations against monsters in enclosed spaces. This special version is equipped with an Aimpoint red dot sight and camoufage.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_rpg7_descr">
    <text>A recoilless single-shot smoothbore grenade launcher equipped with an PGO-7 optical sight (multiplicity of 2.7 diopters). Its large size and weight has made it not too common among the Stalkers, but its destructive power and ease of use has given the launcher its followers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_sig220_descr">
    <text>The only model remaining in production of this series, this popular pistol is characterized by its excellent ergonomics and excellent accuracy. The lowmagazine is compensated for by its power and reliability. This pistol is in high demand among experienced stalkers and mercenaries.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_spas12_descr">
    <text>This smooth automatic shotgun, developed in the second half of the twentieth century, continues to be widely used by various police and army assault units. With its ability to shift modes of fire it has overcome its weight, complexity, and high price to become quite popular in the zone as an effective weapon for combating mutants.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_svu_descr">
    <text>A modernized version of the SVDm 2 sniper rifle, the SVU uses its reduced size to improve on its predecessor. It has a higher rate of fire, less weight, and still maintains the great accuracy from small to medium range. It has become quite popular among the military and stalkers.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_val_descr">
    <text>A Russian modern silent weapon designed for the special forces based on the AS VAL. It allows the user to place effective fire on the armored enemies while not comprimising the user's position. Has an integrated silencer and uses heavy bullet 9x39mm rounds.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_gauss_descr">
    <text>Very high-tech weapon. Known as "Project #62", it was developed in a secret laboratory in the zone. Using a system of electromagnetics, the bullet is able to penetrate extremely well with very little recoil. Energy cell's use particles from certain artifacts.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_beretta_descr">
    <text>Guns from the Beretta series have a worldwide reputation as a reliable, but sometimes unwieldy, weapon. In use by many armies and police forces, it is equally popular with criminals and many others. The Zone does not typically see the newest model of this weapon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="st_wpn_walther_descr">
    <text>From the west, this excellent pistol is highly reliable, very capacious, has good accuracy, and is the best in class ergonomically. Once it hit The Zone, it became one of the most common handguns used among professionals and newcomers alike.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss_descr">
    <text>Made in factories via the use of very high-tech equipment, this energy cell uses an encapsulated piece of the Flash artifact as its energy source.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="ammo-gauss_cardan_descr">
    <text>Built without the special equipment needed, this energy cell has a reduced capacity. It uses an encapsulated piece of the Flash artifact as its energy source.</text>
  </string>

	<string id="st_wpn_mine_name">
		<text>PFM-1 scatterable anti-personnel mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mine_descr">
		<text>PFM-1 used to be a standard-issue anti-personnel mine of the Red Army, employed mainly during the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan. Its widespread utilization during the conflict led to high civilian casualties, especially among children, since randomly scattered mines were often mistaken for toys due to their familiar shape and color. For this reason, the PFM-1 earned a sinister nickname: "Child killer." Since then, the mine has been replaced by newer models. However, as was the case with a variety of other 'retired' weaponry, a large number of these mines has somehow made its way into the Zone, becoming its primary booby-trap explosive. The mine is highly valued mainly for its functionality, user-friendliness, compact size and low weight, while its main drawback is a relatively small amount of explosive material: its power is often insufficient to kill a heavily armored stalker with a single blast. For this reason, the mine should be used in combination with other explosive materials and it acts as an igniter. If it is not armed, the mine will not detonate, even when hit with a gun.\n</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
